## Vitalii Bielievtsov

Software Developer 106 Osprey Crescent, Kanata, ON K2M 2Z8, Canada vitalii.bielievtsov@gmail.com | (343) 204 9199 | Linked in.

#### **SUMMARY**

Front End Developer with a passion for delivering exceptional user experiences, with 3 years of experience in web development. Deep knowledge of JavaScript, Typescript, React, and other web technologies, and understanding of design principles, user interfaces, and best practices.

#### **SKILLS AND AREAS OF EXPRETISE**

- Frontend: ReactJS, JavaScript, Typescript, HTML5, CSS, SCSS, SASS, Chakra UI, Semantic UI, Redux, Context API, REST, GraphQL, styled components, D3, redux saga, SEO optimization, Webpack,
- Backend: NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, Redis, experience in PostgreSQL.
- Testing: black-box, white-box, Enzyme, Jest, react-testing-library, unit, integrational, e2e testing.
- Other: creating feature descriptions, local feature owning, skilled in tracing systems Jira, Miro, Rally, documentation using GitHub, Git, Scrum, Kanban, Confluence, UML, taking part in estimation, retro, and planning sessions, TDD, design patterns.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Software developer – Relevant Software, Lviv, Ukraine

06/2022 - 09/2022

- Worked with business requirements directly with the product owner.
- Developed and high-quality Typescript code using React, react-redux, Context API, Chakra UI, and SCSS.
- Tested codebase with unit tests using Jest and test coverage of the components was higher than 95%.
- The loading time of animated pages was reduced from 4 seconds to less than a second.
- Cooperated with a team of 10 people and ran the frontend of the project.

## Software developer – EPAM Systems, Kharkiv, Ukraine

04/2021-06/2022

- Developed SPA applications using ReactJS, JavaScript, Typescript, and Redux.
- Worked with micro-frontends Webpack Module Federation, split into ten parts.
- Developed applications considering ally 95% of the user interface elements were accessible.
- Implemented i18n using react-intl for 30 languages.
- Collected feature requirements from the client for every product iteration.
- Demonstrated weekly features for the clients, with more than 30 demonstrations.
- Took the lead over 2 main features and released the features on time.
- Refactored legacy code and tech debt.
- Created design documentation using Atlassian Confluence, Miro, and Rally.
- Worked with DSDM and FDD for projects.
- Unit, integration, and e2e tests using react-testing-library, Enzyme, and Jest as a framework (test coverage 90%).

# Software developer – Sigma Software, Kharkiv, Ukraine

03/2020 - 04/2021

- Developed projects using NodeJS, MongoDB, ReactJS, and Redux in a team environment.
- Single developer for a specific client demand project released meeting the 3-week deadline.
- Implemented data visualization using D3 in cooperation with the backend team.
- Conducted ReactJS SPA optimization, and profiling. Reduced render time of pages by 50%.
- Refactored legacy code and tech debt. Increased main Sonar metrics by 30%.
- Tested projects with unit tests using Jest, and increased test coverage from 50% to 70%.
- Worked with product owners as an independent developer.
- Worked on migration of a database from PostgreSQL to MongoDB.
- Junior developer (March 2020) to the Middle developer (November 2020).
- Member of decision-making team.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Software Engineering**, Bachelor

Kharkiv National University of Radio Electronics, Ukraine 2018 – 2022

> University of Ottawa, Canada 2022 – Present

**Digital Transformation and Innovation**, Masters